<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Santa Barbara Hackerspace</title>
    <description>Write an awesome description for your new site here. You can edit this line in _config.yml. It will appear in your document head meta (for Google search results) and in your feed.xml site description.
</description>
    <link>http://sbhackerspace.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://sbhackerspace.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>2017-02-18 19:42:17 -0800</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>2017-02-18 19:42:17 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Eagle Cad Class</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/eagle-cad-class.jpg&quot; class=&quot;fit image&quot; /&gt;
To Sign up please visit: &lt;a href=&quot;http://sbhackerspace.com/shop/&quot;&gt;http://sbhackerspace.com/shop/&lt;/a&gt;
and select the Eagle CAD class and checkout, payment is available via PayPal, credit, cash, or check. If you would like to pay with cash or check please email &lt;a href=&quot;&amp;#109;&amp;#097;&amp;#105;&amp;#108;&amp;#116;&amp;#111;:&amp;#105;&amp;#110;&amp;#102;&amp;#111;&amp;#064;&amp;#115;&amp;#098;&amp;#104;&amp;#097;&amp;#099;&amp;#107;&amp;#101;&amp;#114;&amp;#115;&amp;#112;&amp;#097;&amp;#099;&amp;#101;&amp;#046;&amp;#099;&amp;#111;&amp;#109;&quot;&gt;&amp;#105;&amp;#110;&amp;#102;&amp;#111;&amp;#064;&amp;#115;&amp;#098;&amp;#104;&amp;#097;&amp;#099;&amp;#107;&amp;#101;&amp;#114;&amp;#115;&amp;#112;&amp;#097;&amp;#099;&amp;#101;&amp;#046;&amp;#099;&amp;#111;&amp;#109;&lt;/a&gt; so we can reserver your spot for the class.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a four week class, constisting of a one hour class per week. The class assumes zero knowledge of Eagle CAD and PCB / circuit design, though the depth of the class will likely be informative for those familiar with Eagle CAD. PCBs are the heart of most every modern electronic device and being able to create them can be an extremely useful skill for executing most any electronic device.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://cadsoft.io/&quot;&gt;Eagle CAD&lt;/a&gt; is a PCB (Printed Circuit Board) design tool with a version of the software available for free. It is widely used by the hobbyist community and is a powerful tool for PCB creation. Eagle CAD includes tools for creating a schematic and generating a PCB from the schematic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Below is the class outline which outlines the goals of the class and what will be covered. The class will be taught by Mike “Swiss” Bales and other SB Hackerspace members.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;an-intro-to-using-eagle-cad-to-design-circuits-and-pcbs&quot;&gt;An Intro to Using Eagle CAD to design circuits and PCBs&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;class-outline-and-goals&quot;&gt;Class Outline and Goals:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The goal of this class is to teach participants with no CAD or circuit design knowledge the necessary skills to take an idea and develop it into a working circuit / PCB. PCBs (Printed Circuit Boards) are an integral part of nearly all modern electronic devices. Eagle CAD is one of the most popular entry level tools available for developing schematics and PCBs. The class will cover every step of the PCB design process from schematic design, PCB layout, production, and assembly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;prerequisites&quot;&gt;Prerequisites:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A computer capable of running Eagle CAD (specs and download available at: http://www.cadsoftusa.com/download-eagle/ )&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A desire to learn how to create an electronic device with a PCB&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;class-schedule&quot;&gt;Class Schedule:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The class will be held over the course of three weeks, with one, one hour and a half classes per week. Classes start Thursday 7/7/16 with the next two on the following Thursday evenings (7/14  and 7/21)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;class-schedule-1&quot;&gt;Class Schedule:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Class 1:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why use Eagle CAD&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Installing Eagle CAD (on Windows, Mac, and Linux)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Navigating the Eagle UI&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Creating a new project, Schematic, and PCB&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Installing additional libraries&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using Github for revision control and collaboration&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Class 2:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Adding parts to a schematic&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Connecting components and nets&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Schematic best practices&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Creating a PCB from schematic&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Part placement and signal routing&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PCB layout best practices&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Class 3:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Working in 2 layers, Vias, Planes&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Assembling a completed PCB&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Making a PCB at home / sending a PCB for manufacture&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Soldering&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Debugging PCB errors  and iterating designs&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;class-fee&quot;&gt;Class Fee:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The class fee is $25 for non-members and  covers the materials included in the class and a fee to help fund the space and make more classes like this possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SBHX member’s fee is $20&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We want to make our classes as available as possible, if you would like to attend the class but are unable to pay the fee please email us for other arrangements.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>2015-08-20 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://sbhackerspace.com/2015/08/20/Eagle-CAD-Class.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://sbhackerspace.com/2015/08/20/Eagle-CAD-Class.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Electron Microscope Is Online</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/swiss-holding-sample-retouched.jpg&quot; class=&quot;fit image&quot; /&gt;
After about 3 weeks of working on tracking down manuals and schematics the two Mikes were able to successfully assemble and power up the behemoth Scanning Electron Microscope (SEM) that was donated to the Space by Santa Barbara Infrared. This puts the SB Hackerspace into a small exclusive group of maker spaces which have electron microscopes for use by members and the public.  We are planning on sharing all the technical docs and steps on this blog soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the mean time, here are some photos of this amazing machine in action.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>2015-06-09 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://sbhackerspace.com/2015/06/09/Electron-Microscope-Is-Online.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://sbhackerspace.com/2015/06/09/Electron-Microscope-Is-Online.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
